Whatever you do, do it carefully
Phantom Thread is a drama, romance film directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
In 1950s London, a renowned dressmaker's meticulous lifestyle begins drastically
changing as his relationship with his young muse intensifies.
Reynolds Woodcock, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
Alma Elson, played by Vicky Krieps.
Cyril Woodcock, played by Lesley Manville.
Johanna, played by Camilla Rutherford.
Countess Henrietta Harding, played by Gina McKee.
Dr. Robert Hardy, played by Brian Gleeson.
Phantom Thread is a 2017 psychological period drama film
written and directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
It stars Daniel Day-Lewis, Vicky Krieps, and Lesley Manville, and follows a haute
couture dressmaker in 1950s London who takes a young waitress as his muse.
It is Anderson's first film shot outside the United States, with principal
photography beginning in January 2017 in Lythe, England.
It is also Anderson's second collaboration with Day-Lewis, after There Will Be Blood
(2007), and his fourth collaboration with composer Jonny Greenwood.
Phantom Thread premiered in New York City on December 11, 2017, and was
theatrically released in the United States two weeks later.
It received acclaim for its acting, screenplay, direction,
musical score, costume design, and production values.
The National Board of Review chose it as one of the top ten films of 2017, and
it is widely considered one of the best films of the 2010s.
At the 90th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor (Day-Lewis),
Best Supporting Actress (Manville), and Best Original Score; it won for Best Costume Design.
It also earned four nominations at the 71st British Academy Film Awards, winning
for Best Costume Design, and received two Golden Globe nominations.
The film explores themes of london, england, husband wife
relationship, obsession, dressmaker, fashion designer.
The tone is emotional.